Pedro Scaff

Software Engineer | Bachelor of Engineering | Brazilian / German | pedro@scaff.me | Living in Berlin

About me

I'm a backend focused software generalist with a broad range of skills. I can work with different technologies and learn fast. I have experience working with high quality standards and agile teams. I like setting up processes and helping teams work better and be more productive. I highly value a healthy and happy work environment.

I'm currently working as a software engineer at Vay. I work in a team of four backend engineers developing a ride-hailing platform. We have been developing a distributed system with Golang and Kafka to fulfill diverse requirements, not only from the core service (delivering a vehicle to a customer), but also to manage the fleet status and develop tools for operations.

Experience

Backend Engineer at Vay | Sep 2022 - Current

- Backend development of on-demand ride-hailing platform
- Distributed backend in Golang with Kafka
- Data schemas using protobuf
- Infrastructure with AWS using Terraform
- Development of operations dashboards with Appsmith

Embedded Software Engineer at Vay | May 2020 - Sep 2022

- Development of real-time, low-latency application built using ROS and CEF running on Linux
- Lit Element/Redux/ThreeJS for Javascript WebApp
- Development of embedded/native part using C++
- IPC interface for communication between C++ and JS
- Infrastructure setup using Terraform

Software Engineer at Daimler Mobility Services | August 2019 – May 2020

- Backend development of on-demand fleet API
- Distributed backend in Node.js with Kafka

Software Developer at Pixsy | October 2018 – July 2019

- Frontend development of WebApp using React / Redux
- Setup for test automation infrastructure (Jenkins, Docker)

Software Engineer at HERE Technologies | November 2017 – September 2018

- Frontend development of WebApps featuring 2D and 3D visualizations
- Node.js development of APIs tools and pipelines

Working student as a QA Engineer at HERE Technologies | January 2015 - October 2017

- Automation of functional tests for JS library and WebApp
- Manual testing of JS library API and WebApp
- Setup for test automation infrastructure (Jenkins, Docker)

Private language teacher (german) | July 2012 – July 2013

Skills

- Javascript / Typescript
- Golang
- NodeJS
- AWS
- Terraform
- Rust
- C++

Education

HTW Berlin - University of Applied Sciences | 2014 - 2017

• Computer Engineering, Bachelor

Languages

• Mother language: Portuguese

• Fluent: English and German

• Basic: Spanish and Italian

Social

- Github
- LinkedIn